<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Bishop Scores</string>
    <string name="info_button">More Info</string>
    <string name="disclaimer_action">Disclaimer</string>
    <string name="about_bishop_action">About Bishop Scores</string>
    <string name="about_app_action">About App</string>
    <string name="references_action">References</string>
    <string name="back_action">Back</string>

    <string name="info_disclaimer_title">Disclaimer</string>
    <string name="info_disclaimer_body">
Dear Colleague,\n\nIntervention in the course of pregnancy is always serious business. A Bishop Score can help you plan
how to induce labor when you and your patient together decide induction is appropriate.\n\nCalculators and scoring
schemes are from  published literature (see references). The author of the app has tried to faithfully present the
findings and guidance of others with explanations and discussion while not substituting his own judgment. If you think
I have erred in presentation or explanation, please let me know!\n\nThis app is no substitute for knowledge, training,
and experience in labor induction. The app is merely a quick reference of material you already know.\n\nAnd like any
other calculator scoring scheme, these calculators suggest how you might plan induction for the average patient. But,
they cannot tell you how to manage the single unique patient at hand right now. Individualize your care and be vigilant
for advances and changes in induction management. And most of all, do your own thinking.
    </string>

    <string name="info_about_bishop_title">About Bishop Scores</string>
    <string name="info_about_bishop_body">
Induction of labor is a medical intervention undertaken to bring pregnancy to its conclusion with delivery before
nature intended. As such, some women\'s bodies are more ready for labor while others are less ready. In 1964, Edward
Bishop published his classic paper describing pelvic exam findings which correlated with imminence of spontaneous labor
and, by extension, readiness for induced labor. His score for pelvic exam findings soon took his name as the Bishop
Score. Although his study was about imminence of natural labor and not about the intervention of induction, he asserted
that the score was useful for predicting which women could be induced to achieve a successful vaginal delivery.
Subsequent work confirmed that pelvic findings predicted likelihood of induction success.\n\nOver the ensuing years,
other scoring systems were developed based upon pelvic exam findings and maternal characteristics such as parity,
postdates, and more. The original Bishop Score and all the subsequent ones involved findings and point schemes and
sometimes weighting of factors to arrive at a final score. Most if not all schemes have too many factors and point
systems to memorize.  Paper charts and digital calculators like those in this app are indispensable. The original
Bishop Score of the 1964 paper and the Hughey 1976 critique of the several schemes of the time with its \"modifiers\" to
improve the accuracy are both popular currently and are presented in this app. The third is the 2011 Simplified Bishop
Score. Using modern statistical methods and a large sample size of nulliparas who typically provide the most challenge
to induce, the Simplified Bishop seeks to achieve predictive accuracy as good or better than the original score while
simplifying the number of factors involved for the sake of ease of use.\n\nIn all cases, a woman with a low score is
considered \"unfavorable\" for induction and less likely to arrive at a vaginal delivery with Oxytocin, amniotomy, and
the like. Her chances for success are improved by measures which \"ripen\" or prepare the cervix and produce higher
scores and better readiness for subsequent induction measures. Typical ripening agents include prostaglandins and
mechanical dilators like Foley catheters. When ripening agents produce improved favorable Bishop scores, induction
usually commences.\n\nBut it must be noted that although various papers and guidelines cite score thresholds, these
thresholds are somewhat arbitrary. The success rate difference between Bishop scores of 1 versus 7 is large, while the
difference between 6 and 7 is small, even though the threshold score for favorable induction success is >6 (ACOG, 2009).
There is a continuum of rates of vaginal delivery success. Furthermore, different types of patients and different
situations may warrant different thresholds for who needs ripening and who may proceed to induction. Thus one should
not read these calculators, their scores, and the cited success levels as absolute. Because so many papers and
calculators cite thresholds and offer interpretations, these do, too. You may (and should!) substitute your own
interpretations and thresholds according to your knowledge of the literature and your knowledge of your patient and
her unique clinical situation as you plan induction.\n\nSome Bishop calculators give a percent likelihood of successful
vaginal delivery such as \"score 2 = X%, score 3 = Y%, score 8 = Z%,\" etc, all based upon the stats from the source
paper in the literature. But that would suggest that such numbers generalize and apply to your present patient. Given
how c-section rates were dramatically different in 1964 and 1976 from 2011, and how different papers studying different
populations will have different vaginal delivery rates, I think it would be misleading to cite an absolute percent
likelihood of success that one would be tempted to apply to a current patient under consideration for induction. Using
relative terms like \"favorable\" and \"unfavorable\", even with it\'s inaccuracies, is better.\n\nFinally, do not lose
sight of the fact that a Bishop score does NOT tell you whether to induce. You, the clinician, in concert with your
patient\'s needs, wishes, and values, choose whether and when to bring pregnancy to an end and move a patient towards
delivery with induction. Only when you decide to induce do you employ a Bishop score to tell you whether to ripen first.
\n\n \n\n \n\n
    </string>

    <string name="info_about_app_title">About App</string>
    <string name="info_about_app_body">
Written to put Bishop score calculators in the hands of physicians, midwives, nurses, students, and residents at the
point of care.\n\nContent + Design:\n\t\tJoshua Steinberg MD,\n\t\tUHS Wilson Family Practice Residency,\n\t\tBinghamton NY
\n\nProgrammer:\n\t\tAnchu Lee,\n\t\tBinghamton University\n\nFeedback: jds.pocapps@gmail.com\nPlatform: Android
Lollipop 5.0 - Android Pie 9\nVersion: 1\nLicense: GNU General Public License v3.0\nSource:
https://github.com/leeanchu/BishopScores
    </string>

    <string name="info_references_title">References</string>
    <string name="info_references_body">
\"Pelvic Scoring for Elective Induction\", Edward Bishop, Obstetrics and Gynecology, vol. 24, no. 2, August 1964.\n\n\"An
Evaluation of Preinduction Scoring Systems\", Hughey et. al., Obstetrics and Gynecology, vol. 48, no. 6, December
1976.\n\n\"Using a Simplified Bishop Score to Predict Vaginal Delivery\", Laughon et. al., Obstetrics and Gynecology,
vol. 117, no. 4, April 2011.\n\n\"Induction of Labor\", ACOG Practice Bulletin 107, Obstetrics and Gynecology, vol. 114,
no. 2, part 1, August 2009.
    </string>

    <string name="info_original_score_title">About Original Bishop Scores</string>
    <string name="info_original_score_body">
In 1964 Edward Bishop\'s classic paper (see references) looked at the pelvic exam findings of 500 women and found
correlation between 5 advancing criteria and imminence of spontaneous labor. Knowledge that spontaneous labor was near,
he then asserted, also predicted which patients could successfully be induced to achieve vaginal delivery.\n\nEver since,
the Bishop score has been used to distinguish patients who can be induced straight away from those who would need
cervical ripening before induction measures. Typically one ripens the cervix until a satisfactory Bishop score is
reached, and then induction commences.\n\nPopulation: Bishop does not describe the characteristics of the 500 women
he studied. It has been asserted that he studied mostly or all multiparous women. While the paper does not say so
explicitly, Bishop does say early in his paper that induction of nulliparas should be avoided, suggesting that he
viewed Bishop scoring as a tool for likely use with multiparas.\n\nThresholds: Bishop\'s paper states that a score of 9
or more portends induction success. ACOG\'s most recent Practice Bulletin on induction of labor (see references) states
that a consensus of studies suggests that a Bishop score > 6 is favorable for success and ≥ 9 yields success rates as
good as those of natural spontaneous labor. A look at the Laughon Simplified Bishop paper (see references) not only
shows comparisons between the original Bishop score and the proposed new simplified score, but it also shows success
rate curves for a large cohort of realworld patients, confirming that higher scores (in either scheme) are met with
higher rates of success yet reminding one that thresholds are somewhat artificial as there is a continuum of rising
success rates rather than clear thresholds.
    </string>

    <string name="info_simplified_score_title">About Simplified Bishop Scores</string>
    <string name="info_simplified_score_body">
In 2011, Laughon and colleagues (see references) used modern statistical methods to find which factors are associated
with induction success with an eye towards trying to arrive at a scheme simpler than the classic Bishop score. From a
contemporary electronic multicenter database of more than 200,000 patients they analysed the 5,600 nulliparas
undergoing induction who had a full set of pelvic findings and outcomes recorded. They found that although all of the
Bishop factors correlated with induction success, the factors of dilation, effacement, and station correlated the most,
and the removal of cervical position and consistency did not weaken the predictive power of a simplified scoring scheme.
They then validated the Simplified Bishop Score via bootstrapping (running comparative analyses of old Bishop and new
Simplified Bishop schemes on large randomly selected cohorts of their original data set). The paper demonstrates
statistically and then graphically that the new Simplified Bishop Score yields almost identical predictive results at
each scoring level as the classic Bishop Score.\n\nThresholds: what score is good enough to proceed with induction with
high likelihood of success? The authors of the Simplified Bishop Score paper used Bishop\'s own higher threshold of ≥9 to
declare that success was likely.  An original Bishop score ≥9 correlates statistically with a Simplified Bishop score
of >5.  However, one should note that ACOG\'s standard for a satisfactory Bishop score for favorable outcomes is >6.
Careful review of Laughon\'s statistics and graphs shows that this lower threshold corresponds to a Simplified Bishop
score of >4. Thus the app notes both the >5 and >4 thresholds as potentially meaningful to clinicians and cites them
both with the score results and likelihood of success statement.\n\nPopulation: it should be noted that the Simplified
Bishop Score was developed only on nulliparous patients.Until validated and possibly recalibrated for a parous
population, it cannot accurately be used to guide parous inductions. Although this is somewhat limiting, it is the
nullipara who is most difficult to induce and thus this is the population who needs guidance on induction success the most.
    </string>

    <string name="calc_dilation">Dilation</string>
    <string name="calc_effacement">Effacement</string>
    <string name="calc_station">Station</string>
    <string name="calc_consistency">Consistency</string>
    <string name="calc_position">Position</string>
    <string name="calc_score">Score</string>
    <string name="calc_success">Likelihood of induction success</string>

    <string name="success_unknown">Invalid value</string>
    <string name="success_unfavorable">Unfavorable</string>
    <string name="success_unfavorable_plus">Unfavorable*</string>
    <string name="success_unfavorable_plus_text">* Similar to a 7 in Original Bishop</string>
    <string name="success_favorable">Favorable</string>
    <string name="success_favorable_plus">Favorable*</string>
    <string name="success_favorable_plus_text">* Similar to spontaneous labor</string>

    <string name="value_dilation_0">0 cm</string>
    <string name="value_dilation_1">1 – 2</string>
    <string name="value_dilation_2">3 – 4</string>
    <string name="value_dilation_3">> 4</string>

    <string name="value_effacement_0">0 – 30%</string>
    <string name="value_effacement_1">40 – 50</string>
    <string name="value_effacement_2">60 – 70</string>
    <string name="value_effacement_3">> 70</string>

    <string name="value_station_0">-3</string>
    <string name="value_station_1">-2</string>
    <string name="value_station_2">-1, 0</string>
    <string name="value_station_3">+1, 2</string>

    <string name="value_consistency_0">Firm</string>
    <string name="value_consistency_1">Medium</string>
    <string name="value_consistency_2">Soft</string>

    <string name="value_position_0">Posterior</string>
    <string name="value_position_1">Mid</string>
    <string name="value_position_2">Anterior</string>


</resources>
